<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on blog.cdaf.io</title>
    <link>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on blog.cdaf.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CDAF containerDeploy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/cdaf-containerdeploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/cdaf-containerdeploy/</guid>
      <description>containerDeploy, like containerBuild, is intended for self-hosted agent/runner use cases.
By including the image construction and container execution in source control, the developers remain masters of their own destiny. They can ensure build dependencies are fulfilled while not affecting other users of the agent/runner.
When deploying to remote targets using Web/REST API, or command line interfaces, containerDeploy can exploit the same principles as containerBuild to ensure the required deploy time dependencies are fulfilled, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Validation</title>
      <link>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/variable-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/variable-validation/</guid>
      <description>CDAF provided tabular configuration management files in late 2018, but until now, did not have a convenient way of verifying these properties when they are loaded as variables, nor environment variables, at deploy time. The VARCHK operation has been added to the execution engine to allow different validation rules and logging. The operation syntax is
VARCHK properties.filename There are 5 rules available, two for plain text and three for secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDAF Feature Branch Environments</title>
      <link>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/feature-branch-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 19:45:35 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/feature-branch-environments/</guid>
      <description>The existing feature branch capability in CDAF (Git only, entry.ps1/entry.sh) has been based on docker-compose, for stand-up, test and tear-down environments based on feature branches. For some organizations, where containers are not feasible, i.e. system complexity, proprietary software, a limited number on perpetual environments are available.
The CDAF extension (2.4.5) allows for the targeting of one or more environments, based on branch name prefix (definition file is feature-branch.properties).

Important note: beware of potential environment drift over time as different environments receive different updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming CDAF Policy Changes</title>
      <link>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/upcoming-cdaf-policy-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 19:45:35 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cdaf.io/posts/upcoming-cdaf-policy-changes/</guid>
      <description>Vagrant Rationalisation, Terraform Adoption While support for Vagrant will continue, the extend of regression testing for it will be reduced, i.e. only use cases that I cannot replace with docker will continue to be regression tested. Additional efforts will be make for “Manifest Releases” in Terraform (based on Autonomous Development, Authoritative Release. &amp;amp; Containers at Scale, A Containers Journey.
CentOS Sunset, UBI8 With the end of CentOS in the infancy of CentOS 8, Fedora support by CDAF will based on Red Hat Universal Base Image (UBI).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
